Kenneth Kaijage

586 Falcon Ridge Rd Woodbury, MN 55125 ■ kennykaijage@gmail.com ② (763)-742-2834 Kenny Kaijage Portfolio

SUMMARY

An experienced professional with a Bachelor's degree in Statistics and a minor in Economics with a passion of understanding data. Analytical, action oriented, and hardworking with a strong ability of utilizing critical thinking and teamwork to solve problems.

EDUCATION

University of Minnesota-Twin Cities

Minneapolis, MN

September 2016 – May 2020

Bachelor of Arts, Major in Statistics, Minor in Economics

- Cumulative GPA: 3.08/4.0; Dean's list Spring 2020.
- Area of Emphasis; Statistical Practice.
- Relevant Coursework: Intro to C++; Theory of Statistics; Regression and Correlated Data; Intermediate Microeconomics; Intermediate Macroeconomics; Introduction to Statistical Computing; Applied Statistics; Public Economics; Statistics Designing Experiments; Communication for Statisticians.

SKILLS

Languages: SQL, Python, R, C++, HTML, Java

Libraries: Pandas, Numpy, Matplotlib, Seaborn, Scipy, tidyr, Dplyr, ggplot, sqldf, rodbc

Databases: SQL Server, MySQL, PostGres, Azure Data Studio

Tools: VS Code, R Studio, Spyder, Jupyter Notebook, Github, Tableau, Power BI, Microsoft Excel, Microsoft Power Automate

Certifications: Azure Fundamentals, Azure Data Fundamentals, Northwestern 101: Leading with Analytics, Certificate of Competency in SQL Other: Teamwork, Critical Thinking, Problem Solving, Data Analytics and Reporting, Leadership, Business Process Design, Statistical Analysis

WORK EXPERIENCE

Accenture

Minneapolis, MN

Senior Analyst Consulting Development Analyst November 2022 – Present August 2021 – November 2022

Project Experiences

Data Scientist

August 2023 - Present

• Leveraging Python and Excel to conduct data cleaning and clustering of survey data in CSV files to be later used for data visualization and acquiring insights to help the client understand the level of employee satisfaction across their organizations.

Data Quality Analyst

July 2022 – July 2023

- Created SQL queries for weekly refreshable Excel reports and automated emails to follow up with client project managers for data cleaning purposes in order to improve the data quality and the data integrity of data sources within the business.
- Created SQL queries, data validations and utilizing Excel tools such as Pivot Tables to generate reports and metrics for stakeholders to help them understand how their business was performing.
- Created a Tableau dashboard to conduct data cleaning efforts during the March 2023 fiscal month where the dashboard was used to clean and
 follow up with 26 teams that were not following proper data governance rules of the business in terms of completing deployments and features
 on time while helping the company save costs and use their monthly budget for allocation and optimization.
- Created Excel reports using SQL in order to run monthly audits with the purpose of conducting data cleaning efforts for 100+ projects before
 the month's fiscal date and ensure the client maximized capitalization of over \$50 million dollars in costs.

Business Analyst

January 2022 – June 2022

- Conducted data analysis on the Visit types using Excel to analyze and determine the highest occurrences of a patient's reasons of visit per
 center during the 2019 to 2022 period and used the analysis to create visuals that illustrated five centers with a high visit volume that were to
 be prioritized for the CRM scheduling framework.
- Conducted blocks data analysis using Excel to analyze the highest number of block usage when the patient gets scheduled for a visit and used the data analysis to create visuals and a report that illustrated the highest number of block usage and recommended to the team to remove blocks that were least used from 2021 and onwards.
- Supported the clinical scripting workflow through the creation of clinical scripts and data analysis on keyword mapping and conducted the keyword mapping data analysis using Excel to match symptoms with similar or different naming to ensure that they are accounted in the CRM scheduling framework.

Data Analyst

September 2021 – December 2021

- Created an underlying data process to streamline and automate data from various sources to support reporting and dashboards and
 constructed data tables and views within the ETL development environment in the Microsoft SQL server database for SSI package development
 and the data migration process.
- Created design documents, data tables and structures in the ETL development process and test scripts and assisted in the data cleaning and data organization from the ETL development stage to the data migration stage.
- Loaded the data into the server for clean-up, end-to-end testing and migration to support dashboard building, reporting, and wireframe completion.

US Bank
Global Securities Specialist

Saint Paul, MN

- June 2020 August 2021
 Worked with clients and administrators in creating and managing global accounts for trade.
- Analyzed and rectified invalid trade instructions in the market via SWIFT and inbound SWIFTS (electronically sent trades).
- Made recommendations with other global teams to best meet the client and their business needs.

Worked on internal projects for the specific team and at the global custody level.